Right now, this is the time now to strengthen your relationship with Jesus.
You have listened to the message today; that message is for you and for me.
In the Church we have two Christs:
The Christ of history and story and song - the baby Jesus.
Then, there is this Christ which the Holy Spirit reveals to us.
Which one are you following?
You cannot know Jesus without the help of the Holy Ghost.
Worshipping Jesus without the help of the Holy Ghost is worshipping a god you do not know.
You can read your New Testament over and over and still never find Jesus in it.
You can be convinced that He is the Son of God and still not find Jesus.
You can know about Jesus Christ dying for you and still never know Jesus.
You can be a publisher of the Bible and still never know Jesus.
Where is Jesus? Jesus is in the power of the Holy Ghost.
If you have learnt to worship one Man, you will not worship other men.
Tell your neighbour.
Again.
If you have learnt to worship one Man, you will not worship other men.
Take your pen and write it down.
Because you don't know Jesus that is why you can run to spiritualists.
You can run to this. You can run to spiritualists.
You can run to that. You keep running.
Because you have not learnt to worship one Man.
If you have learnt to worship one Man, you will not worship other men.
I love the Man of Galilee
For He has done so very much for me
He has forgiven me all my sins
And sent the Holy Ghost to me
I love that Man of Galilee
The most dangerous one is that if you are not filled with the Spirit of God,
you cannot obey the written Word.
So then, what is your business with the Bible?
Tell your neighbour: The most dangerous - if you are not filled with the Spirit of God,
there is no way you can obey the written Word!
If you cannot obey the written Word, you quench Him.
So what is your business with the Bible then, when you are not filled with the Spirit,
when you are carrying it, carrying it to cause confusions all over.
You say, "This one is not good. That religion is not good. that one is not good".
That is the confusion we are having all over the world today.
Accusing this, accusing that, other religion, shouting this and that.
Is that what we are taught?
If you are not filled with the Spirit of God, you cannot obey this Bible.
And if you cannot obey this Bible, you quench Him.
So what is your business with the Bible?
"I am Christian" - you see everyone with the Bible.
Everyone with the Cross, big big Bible.
There is no Bible now - it is laptop everyone is having.
The Bible they are supposed to carry is inside the laptop.
Tell your neighbour: If you are not filled with the Spirit of God, you cannot obey the written Word.
And if you cannot obey the written Word, you quench Him.
If your faith is to be a New Testament, if Jesus is to be the Christ of God
rather than the Christ of history and stories, then the illumination of the Holy Spirit
will tell your heart that you are worshipping Him, learning at His feet.
Right now, the business of today: Talk to yourself in your heart; keep your heart busy.
Begin to meditate right now. Meditate in His Word.
Hymn in your heart, spiritual song - keep your heart busy with songs of praise.
I will praise Him
I will praise Him forevermore
Keep your heart busy with this.
Soon, you will be filled.
I will praise Him
Keep your heart busy.
Forevermore
In my situation I will praise Him
I will praise Him forevermore
In my affliction I will praise Him
Your affliction is not to kill you.
It is not to kill you but to strengthen your desire and determination for God.
That's all. That is the purpose of that.
Once you start praising Him, your affliction is not to kill you
but to strengthen your desire and determination for God.
In my situation I will praise Him
I will praise Him forevermore
So, keep your heart busy with this all the time.
That is it.
A break in faith is a break in prayer and a break in prayer is a break with God.
Tell your neighbour.
When you have a break in your heart, when you stop meditating or praising God, satan comes.
Your heart - continue right now.
Are you doing that now in your heart?
"I will praise Him" - when you are eating...
Soon, you will be filled with the Spirit.
That is how to invite the Spirit of God.
Our heart is in a strong conflict - there is a conflict between the flesh and spirit.
"Go - don't go; come - don't come." - that is what is going on in our hearts.
Our heart is busy. There is a conflict.
There is a division in our hearts.
When this is out, the Landlord will take over.
Jesus is not a tenant; He is the Landlord. He is the owner of your heart.
But your heart is divided now: There is for and against in your heart.
When this is cleared, then you invite the Holy Ghost.
Our heart is the contact point, the communication point.
So start with this.
I will praise Him
Continue this in your heart.
By the time you continue this, it is not for you to choose the prayer to offer.
The heart will switch into prayer, switch into speaking in tongues.
You just hear a prayer in your heart.
It's not just for you to choose a prayer; just praise Him.
We are created to praise God.
You are created to praise God, your heart to praise God.
Your heart.
Thank You, Lord.
This is the prayer for you now.
The prayer you have been offering, "Jesus do this for me, Jesus...",
an hour of prayer - that cannot work for you because you are not strong
You are a baby when it come to things of the Spirit.
You need to build your foundation first.
Your foundation is to keep your heart busy with praising.
You are still crawling. You are a baby, just a baby.
You cannot offer prayer here now because whom are you praying to?
- To a god you do not know.
Do you know God? - You don't know God and you are praying.
How can you pray to a god you do not know?
Until you know God before you pray.
If you don't know your Father, can you ask your Father things?
You need to know your Father before you pray, before you ask your Father.
But yet now, you don't know your Father because there is no Holy Spirit.
Tell your neighbour: You need to know God before prayer.
But if you don't know God and you are praying, whom are you praying to?
Foundation first - get your heart to your side.
Your heart is not on your side. It's like your heart is somewhere
When you are looking at me, your heart will say, "Hm, can T.B. Joshua do it?
Hm, look at what is happening. Oh, time is going.
This man should finish quickly. Someone is waiting for me".
Your heart keeps jumping, jumping. Your heart is not on your side.
Until you get your heart to your side, then the Holy Spirit comes in.
Tell your neighbour: Get your heart to your side.
So now your heart:
I will praise Him
I will praise Him forevermore
Let this one keep running in your heart all the time, all day long.
Even when you are sleeping, till you sleep off.
This is why we give you faith bracelets to help on the outside.
Build the foundation before prayer. Know your Father before prayer.
You don't know God and you are praying to God.
How can you pray to a god you do not know? If you know Him, He will answer you.
But this time you pray - no answer because you don't know Him.
Someone keeps telling you, "This is your God, Jesus is your God".
But you are trying to know God in what way? - Without the Holy Ghost.
When you know your God, He will tell you, "Pray this time, meet me this time, appointment this time".
God relates to all like a father.
Like I am talking now - if I hear, "It's alright", I will just say the grace and leave from here.
Tell your neighbour: You need to know God before prayer.
If you don't know God, whom are you praying to?
This is the time for foundation. Get your heart to your side; the Holy Spirit will come in.
Thank You, Lord. This is a special grace.
The Word given to you today - be a hearer, in the name of Jesus!
Right now, open your lips and confess whom you are now.
I am what God says I am!
I can do what God says I can do!
I have what God says I have!
Confess it - that is the platform now.
I am what God says I am!
I can do what God says I can do!
In Jesus Christ's name.
Can someone tell me, "What is your problem now?" You should be able to tell me.
All these challenges, sickness - sickness is not a problem,
setback is not a problem, stagnation is not a problem.
The problem is: We don't know God we are praying to.
If you know me, you talk to me and I will answer you.
If I cannot tell you, I will tell you, "Hold on".
But this is absent. When we pray, we don't hear from God.
"In the name of Jesus, do it for me!" - why can't you wait and let God reply?
We pray and say, "Amen".
It is two sides - you talk, God talks.
That is God - real God.
God talks.
If you are my father, "How are you, sir?"
"I am doing fine."
- "How are doing?"
- "I'm doing okay."
That is God.
But in this case today, we are the only person that is talking.
We never hear from Father, Jesus.
Open your lips.
Make us a channel of faithfulness, a channel of shining light.
Make us Your channel of love.
Make us Your channel of pardon.
Make us Your channel of forgiveness where there is sin.
Make us Your channel of faithfulness, in Jesus Christ's name.
You are a channel of God. As you are going now, anywhere you are, you are a channel.
He has no mouth but your mouth to talk.
He has no hands but your hands.
He has no feet but your feet.
I am a channel of God - channel of love, pardon, forgiveness, faithfulness, obedience.
In Jesus' name. Amen!
I can't hear you.
Amen!
TT Monica Asefa 16/10/18
RV: Mel Flowers 18/11/2018